We've already explored date functions like date trunc and date part.
我们已经了解了日期函数 如 date_trunc 和 date_part
In an upcoming lesson,
在接下来的课程中
we'll dig into even more functions for getting value from dates.
我们将对更多的函数进行深入研究 以从日期中获取价值
The vast majority of analysis you perform in
在绝大多数专业设置中执行的分析
a professional setting will have dates attached to it,
都附有日期
but you might not be able to get value out of them,
如果日期格式不正确
if the dates are not formatted correctly.
就很难从中获得价值
Let's say you've got three separate columns for day,
假设在你特定记录中
month, and year of a given record.
包含日、月和年三个单独的列
Problems like this are common for data that was manipulated in excel at some point,
这样的问题对于某些在 excel 中操作
or exported from a third party system,
或从第三方系统导出的数据
or even data that was just manually entered.
甚至是手动输入的数据都是常见的
In order to really maximize value here,
为了真正使价值达到最大化
you'll need to convert month names into numbers,
需要将月份名称转换为数字
then concatenate all of these fields together along with hyphens,
然后将所有这些字段用连字符连接起来
and then tell the database to understand that the resulting output is a date,
并让数据库知道结果输出是一个日期
which you can do by using the cast function.
这一点可以通过 cast 函数来实现
Let's tackle the first couple steps of this first.
我们首先来看看最初的几步
This first step converted month names into numbers.
第一步将月份名称转换成数字
As you can see, January comes out as one.
如你所见 一月份是被转换为 1
Now let's concatenate that value together with the year and
现在将这个值和年份和日子连结起来
the day to create something that looks like a real date.
使之看起来像真正的日期
For the last step, we'll cast this new field as a date format.
最后一步 将这个新的字段转换为日期格式
You can see here that the database now understands this as a date and has attached
从这里看到 数据库现在可以将其理解为日期
the appropriate zeros to these records so that it reads properly.
并将适当的零附加到这些记录中以方便正确理解
The cast function can be a little tricky to read,
cast 函数可能有一定难度
but luckily, there's also a shorthand.
但幸运的是这里有一个简略的表达方式
Rather than wrapping all of this in a cast function,
不是将其全部内容包含在一个 cast 函数中
we can simply add two colons and then the data type we'd like to cast at
而是可以简单地添加两个冒号
the end of this section.
然后在本节结尾处添加要转换的数据类型
The cast function is most useful for turning strings into numbers or dates.
cast 函数在将字符串转换为数字或日期时最有用
Typically, if you want to turn a number into a string,
通常情况下 要将数字转换为字符串
performing any type of string operation on it like left, right,
执行任何类型的字符串操作（如左、右或子字符串）
or substring will automatically cast the data while performing the operation.
都将在执行操作进行时自动转换数据